Guide to the Azalea Society of America Records
Azalea Society of America Records
- Publications, 1933-2013; 1933 2013; 25.77 linear feet
  - Publications of Other Organizations, 1982-2009
    - The Unique Horticulture Newsletter, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - United States Copyright Office, 1989, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - University of California, 1981 (Halfbox 39, Folder 2)
    - Urban Forest Forum, 1988 (Halfbox 39, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Cooperative Extension, undated (Halfbox 39, Folder 4)
    - Washington Gardener, 1984 (Halfbox 39, Folder 5)
- Research, 1928-2004; 1928 2004; 1.5 linear feet
  The research series consists of materials related to various research projects sponsored by the Azalea Society of America or independent research of various members. Research notes documenting development of different hybrid varieties and correspondence related to this work comprises the bulk of the series. Also included are printed information regarding caring for azaleas, preparing azalea cuttings, different varieties of azaleas, and lists of azalea hybrids; surveys of and about azaleas; and scholarly articles about azaleas and rhododendrons, 1989-2002, most authored all or in part by Dr. Kathleen Kron.
  - Adams, Andy, 1928-1956 and undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Correspondence, reports on azalea breeding.
  - Atlanticum and Weyrichii azaleas. Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - August E. Kerr Research Notes, 1931 (Halfbox 60, Folder 1)
  - Azalea bonsai (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Azalea bloom survey, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Azalea charts, 1971 (Legalbox 61, Folder 5)
  - Azalea module database, 1990-1999, undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Azalea survey, unknown (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Azalea test program, 1982, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Azalea test program. Annual report, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Azalea test program. Charts, [1983-1987?] (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Azalea test program. Correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Azalea test program. Evaluation and results, 1982-1985, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Azalea test program. Plant lists, 1982, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Azalea test program. Procedures, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Azalea test program. Satsuki azaleas, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Azalea test program. Satsukis. 5th year report, [1987?] (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Azalea test program. Test reports, 1986-1989, undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Azaleas in greenhouses, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 21)
  - Bibliography, 2006 (Legalbox 41, Folder 25)
  - Carla hybrids, 1980-1989 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Carla hybrids. Correspondence, 2004 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Charlie Evan's Notes, 1987-1988 (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Cinderella azaleas, 1986-1987 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Cinderella azaleas, 1986-1987 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    Correspondence.
  - Cinderella azaleas. Background research, 1928-1939, undated (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Cinderella azaleas. Background research, 1940-1986 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Cutting process, 1988 (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - Delp rhododendrons (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Dr. Robert J. Miraville Fall Blooming Notes, 1990-2000 (Halfbox 60, Folder 5)
  - Eden hybrids, 1978 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Enclosures from August E Kerr Research Notes "1931", 1992-2001 (Halfbox 60, Folder 2)
  - Garden Plots and Land Surveys, unknown (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Gardening Research and Information, 1990-2005 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - George Harding Azalea Garden, [1992] (Legalbox 41, Folder 1)
  - Glen Dale Preservation Project, 1982-1987 (Legalbox 41, Folder 2)
  - Greenwood azaleas, 1977 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Harding, George W., 1976-1980, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 3)
  - Hirado azaleas, 1961 (Legalbox 41, Folder 4)
  - Hybriding Research Notebook, 1969 (Halfbox 60, Folder 3)
  - Kehr Memorial Garden, 2002 (Legalbox 41, Folder 5)
  - Linwood Hardy azaleas (Legalbox 41, Folder 6)
  - Linwood Hardy azaleas, 1975 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Low-growing azaleas, 1988 (Box 59, Folder 20)
  - Maps, 1965?-1993, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 7)
  - Morrison, B. Y. Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Legalbox 41, Folder 8)
  - Morrison, B. Y. Satsuki descriptions, 1964 (Legalbox 41, Folder 9)
  - Oversize Garden Plot drawings and Surveys, 1979-2005 (Flatfile 6)
  - Plant descriptions (Legalbox 41, Folder 10)
  - Plant lists, 1938-1939, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 11)
  - Pond pumping and filtering system, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 12)
  - Research list, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 23)
  - Research list, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 23)
  - Rhododendrons and Azalea lists, unknown (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Robin Hill azaleas, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 13)
  - Robin Hill azaleas. Development., 1977-1978 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Robin Hill azaleas. Names submitted for registration, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 14)
  - Satsuki azaleas, 1972-1983, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 15)
  - Satsuki azaleas. Correspondence, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 16)
  - Satsuki azaleas. Descriptions, 1983 (Legalbox 41, Folder 19)
  - Satsuki azaleas. Descriptions (1 of 2), undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 17)
  - Satsuki azaleas. Descriptions (2 of 2), undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 18)
  - Satsuki azaleas. Hybrids (Legalbox 41, Folder 20)
  - Satsuki azaleas. Hybrids. Descriptions, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 21)
  - Satsuki azaleas. Plant lists, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 22)
  - Scholarly journal articles and reprint, 1989-1999 (Box 59, Folder 22)
  - Smith, W. David, 1982, undated (Legalbox 41, Folder 23)
  - Special Gardens/Rhododendrons, unknown (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - White, Frank. Interview, 1985 (Envelope 41, Folder 24)